William Francis Gray Swann Papers 1903-1962 Mss.B.Sw1
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1916-1958; 3.0 Linear feet
  - Stromberg, Gustav, 1944-1961; 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Folder 1, 1944-1959 (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1961 (Box 42)
    - Psychic Phenomena and Modern Science, 1957 (Box 42)
  - Strome, Richard, 1955; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Stromeyer, George, 1955; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Stromeyer, Louis, 1923; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Strong, John Donovan, 1931-1932; 6 items (Box 42)
  - Stuart, Joseph, III, 1935; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Sudler, Herman, 1934; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Suffredini, Peter F., 1951; 6 items (Box 42)
  - Suits, C. G., 1946; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Sun Oil Company, 1939-1942; 4 items (Box 42)
  - Sundling, John L., 1946; 4 items (Box 42)
  - Surrette, Albert L., 1955; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Sutherland, Gordon, 1951; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Sutherland, Mason M., 1946-1947; 12 items (Box 42)
    National Geographic Society
  - Sutley, Melvin L., 1955-1958; 6 items (Box 42)
  - Sutton, Richard M., 1942-1950; 7 items (Box 42)
  - Svenska Dagbladet (Stockholm, Sweden), 1936; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Sverdrup, Harald Ulrik, 1926; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Swan, Alfred J., 1951; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Swann, Anne, 1925, n.d.; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Swann, Carolyn (Mrs. W. F.), 1952-56 (Box 42)
  - Swann, Charles Paul, 1937-61; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Folder 1, 1937-40 (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1941-42 (Box 42)
  - Swann, Robert Glenn, 1935; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Swann, William F., 1932-1962; 33 folders (Box 42)
    - Folder 1, 1932-1936 (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1937 (Box 42)
    - Folder 3, 1938 (Box 42)
    - Folder 4, 1939 (Box 42)
    - Folder 5, 1940 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 6, 1940 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 7, 1941 (Box 42)
    - Folder 8, 1942 (Box 42)
    - Folder 9, 1943 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 10, 1943 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 11, 1944 (Box 42)
    - Folder 12, 1945 (Box 42)
    - Folder 13, 1946 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 14, 1946 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 15, 1947 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 16, 1947 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 17, 1948 (Box 42)
    - Folder 18, 1949 (Box 42)
    - Folder 19, 1950 (Box 42)
    - Folder 20, 1951 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 21, 1951 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 22, 1952 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 23, 1952 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 24, 1953 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 25, 1953 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 26, 1954 (Box 42)
    - Folder 27, 1955 (Box 42)
    - Folder 28, 1956 Jan.-June (Box 42)
    - Folder 29, 1956 July-Dec. (Box 42)
    - Folder 30, 1957-1958 (Box 42)
    - Folder 31, 1959 (Box 42)
    - Folder 32, 1960-1962 (Box 42)
    - Folder 33 (Duplicate pubs.) (Box 42)
      Includes copy of Thomas Killian's diss. and article Phys. Rev. (1926)
  - Swann, W. F. G. Lectures. Correspondence, 1926-1934; 8 folders (Box 42)
    - Folder 1, 1926-1929 (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1930 (Box 42)
    - Folder 3, 1931 (Box 42)
    - Folder 4, 1932 Jan.-Mar. (Box 42)
    - Folder 5, 1932 April-Aug. (Box 43)
    - Folder 6, 1932 Sept.-Dec. (Box 43)
    - Folder 7, 1933 (Box 43)
    - Folder 8, 1934 (Box 43)
  - Swann, W. F. G. (Box 43)
    - Memoranda of Engagements, 1933 (Box 43)
    - Memoranda of travels outside the U.S.A., 1942-1956 (Box 43)
    - Patent application: "Mercury Spark Gap", 1929-1932 (Box 43)
    - Plan of Research for Determination of Specific heat, Thermal Conductivity, and Thermal Expansion, 1 item (Box 43)
    - Publications and Correspondence Re: Publications, 1925-1932; 2 folders (Box 43)
      - Folder 1, 1925-1931 (Box 43)
      - Folder 2, 1932 (Box 43)
    - Re: Mrs. W.F.G. Swann (Mabel), 1954; 3 items (Box 43)
      includes Mrs. Swann's obituary
    - Relativity, 1960; 3 items (Box 43)
      "Popular lecture on relativity"
    - Residence Correspondence, 1927-1928; 4 folders (Box 43)
      - Folder 1, 1927-1928 (Box 43)
      - Folder 2, 1929 (Box 43)
      - Folder 3, 1930-1932 (Box 43)
      - Folder 4, 1933-1955 (Box 43)
    - Statement concerning his "Alien Registration", Dec. 5, 1940; 1 item (Box 43)
    - Statement made to American Philosophical Society Committee on Research, 1943 June 4; 3 items (Box 43)
    - Statement of Activities and Organizations, 1914-1918; 4 items (Box 43)
    - Statement Regarding "Deed of Dedication", April 8, 1939; 1 item (Box 43)
    - Swann's Faults on the Cello as Judged by Myself, n.d.; 3 items (Box 43)
    - Trip to Mexico [report], 1943; 2 items (Box 43)
  - Swarthmore Music Club, n.d.; 1 item (Box 43)
  - Swarthmore National Bank & Trust Company, 1932; 11 items (Box 43)
  - Swarthmore Symphony Orchestra, 1945-1954; 24 items (Box 43)
  - Swarthmorean (Swarthmore, Pa.), 1943-1957; 5 items (Box 43)
  - Swaythling, Lady, 1928; 1 item (Box 43)
  - Swezey, Kenneth M., 1931; 5 items (Box 43)
  - Swift, Charles J., 1944; 6 items (Box 43)
  - Swingle, John F. Jr., 1952-1953; 5 items (Box 43)
  - Swartz, Charles D., 1949; 2 items (Box 43)
  - Swope, Charles S., 1945; 2 items (Box 43)
  - Szanto, Jani, 1943-1961; 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Folder 1, 1943-1951 (Box 43)
    - Folder 2, 1952-1961 (Box 43)
  - Tait, H. Sinclair, 1945; 2 items (Box 43)
  - Takayama, Gizo, 1961; 1 item (Box 43)
  - Talley, T. W., 1928; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Tanner, H. G., 1933; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Taschek, R. F., 1957; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tate, John T., 1926-1949; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Folder 1, 1926-1927 (Box 44)
    - Folder 2, 1930-1933 (Box 44)
    - Folder 3, 1934-1936 (Box 44)
    - Folder 4, 1937-1949 (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Dorothy, 1947; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Taylor, E. J., 1950; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Taylor, G. Kirkwood, 1927; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Harvey C., 1946-1951; 7 items (Box 44)
  - Taylor, H. W., 1955; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Hugh S., 1936-1953; 17 items (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Julius H., 1951; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Mykia, 1944; 12 items (Box 44)
  - Taylor, Paul, 1959; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Taylor, S. Herbert, 1944; 5 items (Box 44)
  - Tauber, Gerald E., 1956; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1927-1954; 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Folder 1, 1927-1939 (Box 44)
    - Folder 2, 1949-1954 (Box 44)
  - Teas, J. P., Jr., 1947; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Technical Engineering News, 1931; 4 items (Box 44)
  - Technology Club of Syracuse, Inc., 1932-1935; 19 items (Box 44)
  - Terrell, James, 1959; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Temple University, 1957-1960; 10 items (Box 44)
  - Temple University. Registrar, 1957; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Templin, Lyman J., 1955; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Terry, H. C., 1924-1925; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Thatcher, C. G., 1935; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Thayer, William S., 1917; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Theosophical Society of America, 1961; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Thermal Syndicate Ltd., 1926; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Thimmes, James G., 1947; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Thomas, J. Earl, Jr., 1939; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Thompson, John W., Jr., 1953; 2 items (Box 44)
    Offering a new theory of gravity based on common sense, not mathematics
  - Thompson, F.C.V., 1950-55 (Box 44)
  - Thompson, Fred D., 1950; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Thompson, Hilda (Mrs. F.C.V.), 1959 (Box 44)
  - Thompson, John Peter Stuart, 1953-56 (Box 44)
  - Thomsen, John S., 1959; 5 items (Box 44)
  - Thomson, Charles A., 1947; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Thomson, Elizabeth, 1935-1936; 4 items (Box 44)
  - Thomson, Ellis, 1936; 4 items (Box 44)
  - Thomson, George P., 1946-1961; 10 items (Box 44)
  - Thone, Frank, 1935; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Thurston, L. L., 1948; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tibbalds, W. H. and Son, 1935; 10 items (Box 44)
  - Tiedeman, John A., 1941; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Tietz, John W., 1956; 5 items (Box 44)
  - Tigert, John J., 1935; 11 items (Box 44)
  - Time Magazine, 1935; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Tisdale, W. E., 1924-1925; 4 items (Box 44)
  - Tittmann, Charles, 1953; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tittmann, O. H., 1918; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tobin, Richard, 1930; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tornell, Mrs. B., 1956; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Tokiyoshi, H., 1935; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tompkins, Howard E. Agreement, n.d.; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Torrey, Charles C., 1925; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Toscanini, Arturo, 1943; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Tousey, Richard, 1952; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Town and Country Review, 1935; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Townsend, Anne B., 1944; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tracerlab, Inc., 1950-1951; 6 items (Box 44)
  - Trautman, DeForest L., 1952; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Trautwine, John C, 3rd., 1945; 6 items (Box 44)
  - Treadwell, L. S., 1927; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Trinity College of Music, 1934-1948; 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Folder 1, 1934-1936 (Box 44)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1948 (Box 44)
  - Trumbull, H. L., 1946; 4 items (Box 44)
  - Trump, John G., 1939-1956; 17 items (Box 44)
  - Trytten, M. H., 1943; 1 item (Box 44)
  - Tuckerman, L. B., 1956; 2 items (Box 44)
  - Tunnell; R. M., 1953; 3 items (Box 44)
  - Tupper, K. F., 1953-1954; 24 items (Box 45)
    Includes biographical sketch of Swann
  - Turck, Avis Paine, 1941; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Turck, Fenton B., 1931; 5 items (Box 45)
  - Turnbull, E. Stanley, 1945; 9 items (Box 45)
  - Turner, A. H., 1939; 3 items (Box 45)
  - Tutton, Mabelle, 1937; 3 items (Box 45)
  - Tutwiler, Carrington C., 1924-1927; 3 folders (Box 45)
    - Folder 1, 1924 (Box 45)
      Re: Swann's appointment to the Bartol
    - Folder 2, 1925 (Box 45)
    - Folder 3, 1926-1927 (Box 45)
  - Tuve, Merle A., 1924-1961; 25 items (Box 45)
  - UERMWA, 1947; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Ullmann, H, M., 1936; 5 items (Box 45)
  - Ulrich, David, 1935; 8 items (Box 45)
  - Underhill, Charles R., 1937; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Folder 1, 1937 Jan.-June (Box 45)
    - Folder 2, 1937 July-Aug. (Box 45)
  - Underwood, Roy, 1951; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1926-61; 8 items (Box 45)
  - Union Tank Company, 1937; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United Brewers Industrial Foundation, 1937; 2 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Air Force. Air Materiel Command, 1945-1949; 15 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Air Force. Air University, 1947; 3 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Army Signal Corps, 1943; 2 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Atomic Energy Commission, 1947-1958; 4 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Dept. of Justice - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1956; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United States. Dept. of Labor - Immigration Service (Anne Swann), 1925; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United States. National Bureau of Standards, 1941; 2 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Navy. Inspector of Navy Material, 1950-1952; 17 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Navy. Office of Naval Research, New York, 1952; 2 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Navy Yard, Philadelphia, 1940; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United States. Office of Production Management, 1941; 14 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Office of Research and Development, 1945; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United States. Post Office Dept., 1930-1951; 8 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Provost Marshall, 1942; 1 item (Box 45)
  - United States. Selective Service System, 1942; 4 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Selective Service System. Local Board (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1919; 4 items (Box 45)
  - United States. Treasury Department, 1937-1949; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Folder 1, 1937-1944 (Box 45)
    - Folder 2, 1945-1949 (Box 45)
  - University of Bombay, 1954; 3 items (Box 45)
  - University of California, 1927-1931; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Folder 1, 1927-1929 (Box 45)
    - Folder 2, 1930-1931 (Box 45)
  - University of Florida, 1935; 3 items (Box 45)
  - University of Michigan. Graduate School, 1928-1939; 4 items (Box 45)
  - University of Pennsylvania. Registar, 1948; 1 item (Box 45)
  - University of Puerto Rico, School of Tropical Medicine, 1933; 2 items (Box 45)
  - University of Virginia, 1948; 2 items (Box 45)
  - Unsold, A., 1951; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Urey, Harold C., 1934-1936; 10 items (Box 45)
    Election of I.I. Rabi to the APS
  - Vallarta, Manuel Sandoval, 1949-1955; 8 items (Box 45)
  - Van Allen, J. A., 1948; 2 items (Box 45)
  - Van Canegham, Louise, 1954; 3 items (Box 45)
  - Van De Graaf Generator Correspondence, 1933; 4 items (Box 45)
  - Van Den Burg, William, 1933; 2 items (Box 45)
  - Van Deren, He S., 1936; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Van Der Kamp, Peter, 1953; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Vanderloo, John S., 1954; 2 items (Box 45)
  - Van Der Merwe, C. W., 1937; 3 items (Box 45)
  - Van Devanter, H. R., 1945; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Van De Wall, Willem, 1936; 3 items (Box 45)
  - Van Name, Ralph, 1936; 1 item (Box 45)
  - Van Patter, D. M., 1957; 2 items (Box 45)
  - Van Vleck, J. H., 1928-1948; 7 items (Box 45)
  - Varma, Jagdish, 1961; 8 items (Box 46)
  - Vassar College, 1929-1930; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Vaughan, Major, 1918; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Vaux, George, 1946; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Veblen, Oswald, 1935-1948; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Venable, William Mayo, 1945; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Vernov, S. N., 1961; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Verral, E. J. W., 1935; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Vibrato (Musical Number), n.d.; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Vibro-Ceramics Corp., 1955; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Victor, Carl W., 1950; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Villforth, Fred J., 1956; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Vincent, G. I., 1956; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Vinti, John P., 1949; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Vinz, E. W., 1936; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Vital Speeches, 1935; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Voegeli, Henry, 1936; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Volkers, Clyde E., 1929; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Von Engel, C. E., 1956; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Wade, F. Alton, 1939; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Wagner, L. F., 1960; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Wagner, Walter C., 1949-1950; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Wakefield, Ernest H., 1946-1950; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Wakerling, R. K., 1954; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Walcott, Gregory D., 1949; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Waldhausen, M. H., 1938; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Waldman, Glenys, 1956; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Walker, Dorsey E., 1950; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Walker, F. Allyn, 1952; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Walker, Owen, 1943-1958; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Walker, Robert B., 1942; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Wallace, Mary Bruce, 1936; 8 items (Box 46)
  - Walters, Raymond, 1931; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Wannemacher, Edward H., 1945; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Ward, Henry B., 1935; 10 items (Box 46)
  - Warden, Mrs. W. B., 1951-1953; 9 items (Box 46)
    Concerning the loan of a harp
  - Wardlaw, F. L., 1928; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Warfield, Calvin N., 1941; 6 items (Box 46)
  - Warga, Mary E., 1960; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Warner, M. Burrage, 1936; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Warren, D. T., 1955; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Warren, S. Reid, Jr., 1936-1940; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Warshaw, H. D., 1944-1951; 6 items (Box 46)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D. C.), 1918; 8 items (Box 46)
  - Waterhouse, Maj., 1951; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Waterman, Alan T., 1928-1958; 12 items (Box 46)
  - Waters, Blanche R., 1945; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Watkins, S. C. G., 1924; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Watson, Bernard B., 1949; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Watson, W., 1907-1911; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Watson, W. H., 1954; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Watson, William W., 1940; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Weakley, Emeline, 1951; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1934-1960; 12 items (Box 46)
  - Webb, Harold W., 1924-1930; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Webb, Julian H., 1946-1951; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Webb, Wayne, 1950; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weber, A. H., 1937; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Weber, Ernst, 1938; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Weber, H. F., 1952; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weber, Louis R., 1951; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Webster, W. W., 1937; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Weidler, S. E., 1956; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Weil, George L., 1955; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Weinberger, Julius, 1956; 8 items (Box 46)
    Psychic research
  - Weiner, Theodore, 1949; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Weiss, Myron, 1951; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Weiss, R. A., 1949; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weisskopf, V. F., 1953; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weld, LeRoy D., 1932-1933; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Wellever, Elsie, n.d.; 8 items (Box 46)
  - Wellington, Anne, 1938; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Wells, W. F., 1937-1939; 11 items (Box 46)
  - Wendt, Gerald, 1936-1958; 31 items (Box 46)
  - Wemer, F., 1918-1925; 4 items (Box 46)
  - Western Electric Company, 1935; 6 items (Box 46)
  - Westover, O., 1935; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Wetherill, Samuel P., 1956; 3 items (Box 46)
  - Wetlesen, J., 1925; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weyer, Howard M., 1935-1936; 6 items (Box 46)
  - Weygandt, Cornelius N., 1961; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Weyl, F. Joachim, 1955; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Wheeler, John A., 1945-1961; 5 items (Box 46)
  - Wheeler, Joseph L., 1931; 3 items (Box 46)
  - White, Bertha D., 1933-1935; 16 items (Box 46)
  - White, J. Paul, 1955; 2 items (Box 46)
  - White, Marsh W., 1954-1955; 9 items (Box 46)
  - Whitehead, W. D., 1953; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Whitlock, J. F., 1932; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Whitney, 1921; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Wichmann, Russel G., 1947; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Wieckowski, Philip, 1951; 2 items (Box 46)
  - Wigand, A., 1920; 1 item (Box 46)
  - Wiggins, Thomas A., 1950; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wigner, Eugene P., 1947-1957; 18 items (Box 47)
  - Wilcox, Maurice J., 1959; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Wilets, Lawrence, 1958; 4 items (Box 47)
  - Wiley and Son, 1936; 6 items (Box 47)
  - Willaman, J. J., 1930; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Willard, Harvey B., 1957; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Willets, W. R., 1953; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Williams, Clarke, 1946; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Williams, Craig G., 1956; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Williams, J. Paul, 1956; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Williams, Margaret L., 1945; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Williams, R. J., 1956; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Williamson, Alix B., 1939; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Williamson, R. C., 1935; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Williamson, R. D., 1922-1926; 15 items (Box 47)
  - Willits, Joseph H., 1937-1938; 5 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, C. T. R., 1919; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, Courtney, 1951; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, H. A., 1926-46; 8 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, Hugh, 1954; 4 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, Jack T., 1947; 4 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, Ronald H., 1958; 6 items (Box 47)
  - Wilson, W., 1925; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Winchester, George, 1920-1921; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Windrim, John T., 1929; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Winther, Aage, 1955-1956; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Winzen, O. C., 1947; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wiswesser, William J., 1945; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Witcomb, G. H., 1953-1962; 11 items (Box 47)
  - Witt, William, 1935; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wodal, Francis A., 1936; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wold, P. I., 1936; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Wolff, Katharine, 1945; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wood, Fred J., 1935; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Wood, Harry O., 1919-1921; 8 items (Box 47)
  - Wood, Robert Williams, 1936-1951; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Woodley, Sam, 1937-1940; 11 items (Box 47)
  - Woodruff, Albert E., 1924-1954; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Woods, E. K., 1942; 5 items (Box 47)
  - Woodward, W. M., 1951; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Workman, E. J., 1930-1934; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Folder 1, 1930-1931 (Box 47)
    - Folder 2, 1932-1934 (Box 47)
  - Worner, Ruby K., 1933-1934; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Wright, C. S., 1934; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Wright, William E., 1954-1960; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Folder 1, 1954-1955 (Box 47)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1960 (Box 47)
  - Wroth, Edward, 1951; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Wyer, Edward, 1935; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Wylie, C. C., 1936; 5v (Box 47)
  - Yaglou, C. P., 1928; 4 items (Box 47)
  - Yale University, 1925-1932; 5 items (Box 47)
  - Yenching University, 1933; 5 items (Box 47)
  - Young, Dewitt, 1953; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Young, John Wesley, 1932; 13 items (Box 47)
  - Young, Pauline V., 1948-1949; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Young, R. W., 1945; 2 items (Box 47)
  - Young, Robert R., 1946; 4 items (Box 47)
  - Young, Robert, Jr., 1936; 3 items (Box 47)
  - Youngman, Grant, 1927; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Yule, John, 1935-1943; 5 items (Box 47)
  - Zanstra, H., 1925-1960; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Folder 1, 1925-1926 (Box 47)
    - Folder 2, 1927-1960 (Box 47)
  - Zeleny, Anthony and Henry A. Erikson, 1938; 1 item (Box 47)
  - Zeleny, John, 1923-1940; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Folder 1, 1923-1924 Mar. (Box 48)
    - Folder 2, 1924 Apr.-1940 (Box 48)
  - Ziegler, Hans, 1938; 4 items (Box 48)
  - Zimmerman, E. E., 1932; 4 items (Box 48)
  - Zimmerman, H. F., 1936; 3 items (Box 48)
  - Zirkoff, Boris D., 1945; 4 items (Box 48)
    Theosophy
  - Zorn, Jens C., 1961; 3 items (Box 48)
  - Zuckerkandl, Victor, 1945-1946; 7 items (Box 48)
  - Zumstein, R. V., 1927; 1 item (Box 48)
  - Zweiffel, Paul F., 1957; 5 items (Box 48)
  - Zwick, Fred D., 1946; 2 items (Box 48)
  - Zworykin, V. K., 1944; 3 items (Box 48)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1960; 2 items (Box 48)
- Series II. Articles and lectures, 14.5 Linear feet
  - Abnormality in cosmic ray absorption in lead at low latitudes (Box 49)
  - Absence of ionization by electrons with speeds comparable with that of light (Box 49)
  - Absence of ionization by electrons with speeds comparable with that of light (draft) (Box 49)
  - Acceleration of a fragment, March 1, 1954 (Box 49)
  - Acceleration of particles, etc. (Sweden), 1956 (Box 49)
  - Acceleration to cosmic ray energies by betatron action (Box 49)
  - Acoustics of Music (Philadelphia Musical Academy) (Box 49)
  - Acquirement of cosmic ray energies by electromagnetic induction (I) (Box 49)
  - Acquirement of Energy by Charged Particles un the the Influence of Changing Magnetic Fields (Box 49)
  - Address (Association of Harvard Clubs, Belleview-Stratford), May 17, 1928 (Box 49)
  - Adult education on TV (Box 49)
  - Akimoff Manuscripts (Box 49)
  - Albrecht, H. O. and M. V. Scherb. Memorandum (Box 49)
  - Albrecht, H. O. Problem, Purpose and Difficulties (Box 49)
  - Alternating currents in cables, etc., with special reference to the fundamental significance of resistance (Box 49)
  - American Philosophical Society. Applications for grants (29 folders) (Box 49-50)
  - American Society of the Ancient Instruments. Speech, April 6, 1938 (Box 50)
  - American Society of the Ancient Instruments. Speech...University Museum (Box 50)
  - Analogy between dynamics and coelfrets of induction (unfinished) (Box 50)
  - Antarctic expedition (Finn Ronne) (Box 50)
  - Application and testimonials (Box 50)
  - Art and music (Box 50)
  - Asphalt (Box 50)
    - Memorandum concerning partial systems re: asphalt (Box 50)
    - Memorandum concerning the asphalt program (Box 50)
    - Memorandum concerning the dynamics of asphalt (Box 50)
    - Memorandum: Breaking strength of asphalt, June 27, 1955 (Box 50)
    - Relation between breaking strength of asphalt and Philippoff's experiments, June 27, 1955 (Box 50)
    - Another approach to the stress formulation for asphalt (Box 50)
  - Atmospheric electric observations taken at the University of Chicago during the eclipse, January 24, 1925 (Box 50)
  - Atmospheric electricity (Encyclopedia Britannica) (Box 50)
  - Atmospheric electricity and allied phenomena, May 1942 (Box 51)
    Radio talk over WRUL
  - Atmospheric electricity, 1952, 1952 (Box 51)
    Cambridge, Also Sigma Xi
  - Atmospheric electricity, Oct. 16, 1961 (Box 51)
    American Institute of Medical Climatology, at Franklin Institute
  - Atmospheric electricity (lecture notes) (Box 51)
  - Atmospheric-electric phenomena... (progress report by committees) (Box 51)
  - Atomic bomb defense (Box 51)
    - Answers to memo: Philadelphia Test Exercise (Box 51)
    - Atomic bomb effects and the fire fighters (Box 51)
      By E. J. Kekoe and F.L. Brannigan
    - Memorandum (Box 51)
    - Memorandum concerning apparatus to purchase (Box 51)
    - Memorandum concerning the size of the atomic bomb in determining lethal range (Box 51)
    - Memorandum from Mandeville (Box 51)
    - Memorandum to H. B. Allen, October 20, 1950 (Box 51)
    - Tentative proposed program for training (Box 51)
  - Atomic bomb detection (Box 51)
    Memoir by CEM with notes by Swann sent to Payne
  - Atomic energy (Box 51)
    Sent to Elliott, Aero Digest
  - Atomic energy, March 12, 1953 (Box 51)
    Talk at Temple University
  - Atomic energy. Statement by Swann (Box 51)